news-gazette.com 2019-11-30

# Privacy Policy | Site | news-gazette.com

  **The News-Gazette Online Privacy Policy**

Last revised July 2013

Web sites of The News-Gazette Inc., including but not limited to, news-gazette.com, wdws.com and whms.com take your privacy concerns seriously. The following policy explains our position on information gathering and how we intend to use any user data we may collect from our users.

Please note that this policy applies only to information collected by news-gazette.com and affiliated Web sites. It does not apply to information obtained or used by The News-Gazette or its affiliates through other non-digital means.

Understanding that Internet technologies change rapidly, we may change this policy at any time. Such changes to this policy will be incorporated into this policy as soon as convenient for us. Your use of this Web site means you accept this policy and any of its changes whether displayed here or not.

You can visit many pages on our site without providing any information. You may provide personal information when you participate in contests, sign up for restricted content, register for interactive areas of our site, such as photo galleries, comments, weblogs, etc.

Unless you are signing up for or inquiring about a subscription to our newspaper or online products, we will not give your phone number to our telemarketing department. We will not sell your e-mail address to any company, for any mailing list, unless you specifically give us consent to do so. We will use your information only as permitted by law.

 **Information about you specifically**

You can access our Web site home page and browse most of our sites without disclosing personal data. We may collect and store personal data or other information that you voluntarily supply to us online while using our Web site.

When you fill out a form on our site, we typically ask for demographic information like this: name, address, daytime phone, e-mail address and age. We use names, addresses, phone numbers and e-mail addresses to notify contest winners; or to contact Digital Access subscribers to verify subscription information; or to contact you about subscription offers. We use some of the information in aggregate form to learn more about our visitors.

We do not sell or use any of this personal information outside of our company. We do not disclose your personal information to any third party unless compelled by law. All of our employees who have access to your personal information are obliged to keep it confidential.

We only send e-mail to you if you have provided information to us regarding your e-mail address. For example, there is an option on contest entry forms to choose to be notified of future contests by e-mail. If you click "yes," we may e-mail you when we begin a new contest. If you click "no," we'll leave you alone. If you don't want to receive these e-mails any more, use the instructions included in the footer of the emails to unsubscribe from the list.

Should you connect through your social network account such as your Facebook or Yahoo! Account, we may automatically collect profile information. We use this information to better the delivery of content and to accurately measure site traffic.

If you wish to forward the link to an article online to a friend, we will ask that you give us your friend’s name and e-mail address. While we collect this information, we do not sell, rent or market your friend’s personal information to third parties.

 **Information about you in general**

We do collect statistics about our readers. For example, our statistical logs identify the browsers people use to get to our pages; (e.g. Chrome, Firefox or Internet Explorer), the IP addresses of the computers used to access our pages and the computers' operating systems (e.g., Windows 8 or Mac OS). It does not gather visitors’ e-mail addresses or their identities. These are only collected in aggregate. We cannot identify individuals who simply look at our pages who have not previously become a digital subscriber to news-gazette.com. However, if you are a digital subscriber, we will know whether it is you looking at our pages because of our automatic authentication system.

We may share aggregate information with advertisers or business partners. For example, an advertiser may want to know the age breakdown of the people who enter our contests or whether the people who visit our calendar are coming from local Internet service providers.

 **Children's privacy**

We are particularly concerned with providing a safe online environment for children. We do not knowingly collect or solicit personally identifiable information from or about children under the age of 13. We do not allow anyone under the age of 13 to participate in or register for online contests. If we discover that we have received any information from a child under 13 in violation of this policy, we will delete that information immediately. If you believe The News-Gazette Online has any information from or about anyone under 13, please contact us at our feedback form.

 **Information collection**

We may also collect information from standard web data means. The Site may use browser cookies, flash cookies, pixels, and other technology to deliver and capture information such as IP addresses, MAC address, or other device identifiers, including mobile device model numbers.

We may use a standard feature found in browser software called a “cookie” to enhance your experience on the Web site. Cookies are small files that your Web browser places on your hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your e-mail address or other personally identifiable information.

We use cookies in a variety of ways. We do not collect any information from this limited use of cookies. We may also use it to track the number of entries in some of our contests or features. Advertising vendors that serve ads into our site may also use their own cookies.

We may collect location information provided to us through webforms, contest entries, sweepstakes entries, and other user provided means, as well as through technology and browser unique identifiers. The latter information tells us the geographical location of the device and allows us to calculate accurate statistics regarding our site usage. This information is automatically passed from device browsers to our Site.

 **Information collection by other people**

Our Web site may allow you to communicate with other site visitors or to post information to be accessed by others. When you use these services, your data may be collected by other visitors.

In addition, we occasionally have banner advertising from advertising networks or providers that use cookies. For more on those advertisers’ approach to privacy, you need to go to their policies. We do not know what information these third parties may collect.

We strongly advise that individuals be careful and responsible when online. You should take care when voluntarily disclosing personal information in such areas of the Web site as comments areas, weblogs, etc. Such information can be viewed publicly and collected for use by parties not associated with The News-Gazette without our knowledge. This may result in unsolicited e-mail and other contacts from individuals not employed by The News-Gazette. Such activities are beyond the control of The News-Gazette and this policy.

 **Credit Card information and secure transmission**

If you use a credit card to pay for subscriptions or merchandise, we will not keep your credit card information on any of our computers, once the transaction has been processed. Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology from DigiCert is used to encrypt and protect your credit card account information, and transactions are carried out on a secure server.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100 percent secure, especially, unencrypted information. We do our best to protect your personal information, but we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

For more information about Internet privacy, visit the Electronic Frontier Foundation at <http://www.eff.org/>.

If you have questions about our privacy policy, please contact The News-Gazette’s Electronic Publishing Department by using our feedback form.

## {{ type }}

## {{ closing.location.name }}

### {{ closing.name }}

Type:  {{ closing.type }}    
Date:  {{ closing.date | formatDate }}    
Information:  {{ closing.information }}    

Recent bookings from the Champaign County Correction Center. [View all](https://bookings.news-gazette.com/)
